Guide to the Felix Bloch Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- PUBLICATIONS, SERIES V
  - REPRINTS
    - The Principle of Nuclear Induction, Les Prix Nobel en 1952, Stockholm: Norstedt & Soner 83-96., (1953) (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Nuclear Magnetism, American Scientist 43.1 48-62., (1955) (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Recent Developments in Nuclear Induction, Phys. Rev. 93 944 (T)., (1954) (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Line-Narrowing by Macroscopic Motion, Phys. Rev. 94 496-497 (L)., (1954) (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Contributions to Study of Nuclear Magnetism: Three Studies, (with J. Arnold and W. Anderson) CERN 55-18, (1955). (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Dynamical Theory of Nuclear Induction II, Phys. Rev. 102 104-135., (1956) (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Generalized Theory of Relaxation, Phys. Rev. 105 1206-1222., (1957) (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Theory of Line Narrowing by Double-Frequency Irradiation, Phys. Rev. 111 841-853., (1958) (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Methods and Applications of Nuclear Magnetism, Proc. of the R. A. Welch Foundation Conference on Chemical Research II 145-164., (1958) (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Zur Wirkung ausserer elektromagnetischer Felder auf kleine Systeme, Werner Heisenberg und die Physk unserer Zeit Verlag Friedr. Vieweg und Sohn, Braunschweig 93-102., (1961) (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Energetic Stability of Persistent Currents in a Long Hollow Cylinder, (with H. E. Rorschach) Phys. Rev. 128 1697-1714., (1962) (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Reminiscences of Niels Bohr, Phys. Today 16.10 32., (1963) (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Torque Upon a Rotating Superconductor, unpublished, (1963). (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Off-Diagonal Long-Range Order and Persistent Currents in a Hollow Cylinder, Phys. Rev. 137 A787-A795., (1965) (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Introduction: Some Fundamental Aspects of NMR, NMR in Chemistry 1, 1-6., (1965) (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Some Remarks on the Theory of Superconductivity, Phys. Today 19.5, (1966). (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Flux Quantization and Dimensionality, Phys. Rev. 166.2 415-423., (1968) (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - A Simple Interpretation of the Josephson Effect, Phys. Rev. Letters 21 1241-1243., (1968) (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - Josephson Effect in a Superconducting Ring, Phys. Rev. B 2.1 109-121., (1970) (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - A Short History of Superconductivity, J. Polymer Science C 29.1 1 (A)., (1970) (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - Resonance, Pure and Applied Chemistry 32 4B 1-8., (1970) (Box 46, Folder 26)
    - Superfluidity in a Ring, Phys. Rev. A 7.6 2187-2191., (1973) (Box 46, Folder 27)
    - Reply to 'Free Energy Minima for Helium in a Ring, Phys. Rev. A 10.2 716., (1974) (Box 46, Folder 28)
    - Josephson Effect in a Superconducting Ring, Science and Culture 40.9 377-408., (1974) (Box 46, Folder 29)
    - David Locke Webster, Yearbook of the American Philosophical Society 107., (1977) (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - Dirac Equation of the Electron in a Magnetic Field, Phys. Rev. A 25.1 102., (1982) (Box 46, Folder 31)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1986-093
  This addenda to the papers of Felix Bloch contains an additional four boxes of outgoing correspondence of Bloch, 1958-1974, and of his secretary Marion M. Middleton, 1962-1974; grant files; and a few miscellaneous files.
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1958-62 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1962-64 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1964-65 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1966-68 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1971-73 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1971-73 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1973-75 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1976-79 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1968-70 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1969-71 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1971-73 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence:, 1973-74 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Biographical and Bibliographical Info. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Papers by Bloch and Others (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Marion M. Middleton, outgoing correspondence, 1962-67 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Marion M. Middleton, outgoing correspondence, 1967-70 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Marion M. Middleton, outgoing correspondence, 1970-74 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Physics 210 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bloch Reprint Requests (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bloch Reprint Requests (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Interdepartmental Memos (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Paul Berdahl (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Proposal for Renewal of NONR 225(19), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Proposal for Renewal of NONR 225(75), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Proposal for Renewal of NONR 225(75), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Proposal for Renewal of NONR 225(75), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Proposal for Renewal of NONR 225(75), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Proposal for Renewal of N0014-67-A-0112-0047, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Proposal for Renewal of N0014-67-A-0112-0047, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - NONR 225 (75) Account Sheet (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - NONR 225 (75) Consultation (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - NONR 225 (75) Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - NONR 225 (75) Reports (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - NONR 225 (75) Request Approval Expend (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - NONR 225 (75) Travel (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - NONR 225 (75) Budget and Commitment Statements (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1990-099
  This addenda to the papers of Felix Bloch contains an additional 18 boxes of miscellaneous correspondence, writings, research notes, and official papers (business, legal, and academic matters). These materials were filed in the approximate order in which they were received, by subject. Correspondence is accordingly interfiled with other materials.
  Some subjects of interest include the over fifteen years worth of memos, letters, and departmental minutes regarding the relationship between the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center (SLAC) and the Physics Department (boxes 8 and 9) as well as the correspondence and papers of the Physics Department appointments committee (box 10). Also of note are the manuscripts for numerous talks given by Bloch between 1955 and 1982 (boxes 3, 4, and 5) and a series of government requisition forms dating from Stanford's involvement in the Manhattan Project (box 7).
  - Two Papers: Nishiyama and Carballo/Ruvalds (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes on the Nishiyama and Carballo/Ruvalds paper (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notebook entries:, 9/22/1970-11/28/1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notebook entries:, 3/31/1971-4/11/1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notebook entries: (pp. 1-43), 4/6/1970-6/26/1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notebook entries: (pp. 44-143), 6/27/1970-4/22/1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notebook entries: (pp. 134-165), 6/19/1971-7/10/1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notebook entries: (pp. 166-204), 7/15/1971-8/8/1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Paper: Chang/Rorschach; Rorschach/Bloch Correspondence:, 6/1972-8/1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Paper: Paul Berdahl (One-Dimensional Bose Gas) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Density and Phase Variables in the Theory of Bose Systems: Bogolubov's Transformations:, 12/1975; 10/1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Interaction of Bose (Bogolubov) and Ferini (Tomonaga) Particles (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notebook: Draft of paper Density and Phase Variables in the Theory of Interacting Bose Systems (pp. 1-39) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notebook: Draft of paper (cont.) Density and Phase Variables... (pp. A1-74) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Revisions and notes: Density and Phase Variables... (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notebook: Revisions of Density and Phase Variables... (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Notebook: Revisions of Density and Phase Variables... (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notebook: Draft of Density and Phase Variables... (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notes and materials for seminars on Bose Systems (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bloch Articles:, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Problem Sets from Physics 171: Winter 1968-1969, Winter 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Press Releases re: Address How I Became a Physicist, January, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Diagrams, Equations:, circa 1982 Mar (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Notes:, ca.4/1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Proofs, graphs (14pp. -- missing pp.1-3): Pamphlet:, no date. 10/1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Notes on Thermal Equilibrium:, no date (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Outline, notes on Fundamentals of Statistical Mechanics:, no date (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Article: Schalow; Commencement Address: Correspondence re: Commencement Address, 6/13/1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Res Jost: Correspondence, Article:, 4/1977-12/1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Articles re: Zeugmatography:, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Gibbs Text [incl. Stanford Parking Permit used as a bookmark:, (1960) 1982] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence re: Los Alamos Nat'l Laboratory 40th Anniversary:, 9/82-5/83 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Handout/Study-guide:, no date (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: [unknown signature]:, 11/1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Bloch, Mott, and Seitz, (10/25/1978 - 2/15/1980) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Papers from the conference Beginnings of Solid State Physics (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: Bistability and the Onset of Chaos (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Articles on Chaos (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Copies of Correspondence with Niels Bohr (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Proofs, Overheads on Nuclear Magnetic Resonance: Past, Present, and Future:, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lecture notes, Overheads on the Josephson Effect:, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes, Overheads on Superfluidity:, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Early Days of NMR:, 1972, 1978, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Quantum Statistics of Ideal Gases:, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Quantum Statistics:, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Statistical Mechanics:, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Statistical Mechanics:, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Statistical Mechanics (Photocopies):, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Statistical Mechanics (Photocopies):, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Notes for lectures at Howard University:, 1/26/1967-1/27/1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Notes for lectures:, 9/1964-2/1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bohr Commemorative Lectures (Draft, typescripts):, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Bloch, Rosenfeld, (8/20/1964-4/8/1965) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Reminiscences of Niels Bohr:, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Articles on NMR Imaging:, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Notes for lecture on Kernmagnetismus (Zurich):, 2/1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Talk from the conference 40 Years of Electrons in Metals:, 10/25/1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Talks: How I became a Physicist: and My Beginnings as a Physicist:, 1/20/1970 11/19/1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Writings on The Early Days of Quantum Mechanics:, 1976-1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Talk: The Beginnings of NMR:, 5/1971, 8/1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts: Talks, (6/1955-1958) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts: Talks, (5/19/1959-12/13/1961) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts: Talks, (1/24/1962-2/18/1964) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts: Talks, (2/24/1969-11/18/1979) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts: Talks, (nd: ca.1951- ca.1971) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts: Talks, (1971-1982) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts: Talks on Quantatized Flux, (1961-1968) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Notes, Articles: Superfluidity in rings, (1972-1974) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Typescripts, Notes: Talks, (1971-1972) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Typescripts of Talks (Bloch, Heisenberg):, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Reminiscences of Niels Bohr: Manuscripts, Typescripts, (1963) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Notes, Correspondence: Bombay lectures, (1962-1963) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Reminiscences of Heisenberg and the Early Days of Quantum Mechanics Talk for the American Physical Society:, 4/26/1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Article for Encyclopedia of Physics (Notes, Drafts, Proofs, Correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reminiscences of Heisenberg and the Early Days of Quantum Mechanics Correspondence, Proofs for Physics Today:, 4/13/1976-1/5/1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bloch articles (used by Richard Hofstadter) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bloch testimonials (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Obituaries of Heisenberg (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - NDRC Requisitions:, 6/24/1942-8/11/1942 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - NDRC Requisitions:, 8/13/1942-9/4/1942 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - NDRC Requisitions:, 9/4/1942-10/12/1942 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - NDRC Requisitions:, 10/12/1942-11/25/1942 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - NDRC Requisitions:, 12/3/1942-1/19/1943 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - NDRC Requisitions:, 2/11/1943-5/25/1943 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - NDRC Requisitions: (also: budget material, graph), 6/14/1943-6/29/1943 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Clearence, Security Correspondence:, 7/6/1943-8/9/1954 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Security, material request forms:, 8/20/1954-11/16/1960 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit Correspondence:, 9/2/1964-4/20/1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit Correspondence:, 5/18/1965-2/2/1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit Correspondence:, 7/26/1967-8/3/1967 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit Correspondence:, 8/24/1967-9/20/1967 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Elion v. Varian Associates Correspondence:, 3/27/1962-8/9/1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Elion v. Varian Associates Correspondence:, 5/15/1963-12/2/1964 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Bloch-Packard-Shoolery: Patent Application #454,272 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Foreign and Domestic Patent Application Material:, 4/30/1958-6/28/1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - British Patents Correspondence:, 6/30/1959-6/5/1961 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - German Patent Application Correspondence:, 11/19/1959-1/30/1963 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Gulf Oil License Correspondence and Press Releases:, 8/30/1962-5/16/1963 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - License Agreement Correspondence:, 3/12/1959-5/21/1959 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - License Agreement Littlemore Scientific Engineering Company:, 9/1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Byron-Jackson/Schlumberger Agreement:, 8/11/1962-2/15/1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Byron-Jackson Agreement:, 7/1964 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit License Agreement Correspondence:, 6/19/1967-6/29/1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit License Agreements:, 6/8/1967-6/15/1967 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Patent Infringement Correspondence:, 4/21/1964-1/25/1966 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Information on NMR/EPR Equipment by JEOL:, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - (Report on) Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 6/10/1971 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Project M Correspondence:, 1/31/1957-2/23/1957 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 4/10/1956-12/12/1961 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 1/11/1962-5/1/1962 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 5/11/1962-9/26/1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 9/28/1962-10/27/1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 10/29/1962-12/5/1962 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 1/4/1963-11/12/1963 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 5/21/1964-3/11/1966 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 1/15/1970-12/17/1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 4/5/1971-8/11/1971 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 1/2/1972-11/15/1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC:, 1/4/1973-3/21/1973 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Relations between the Physics Department and SLAC, Spectrometer Question:, 10/27/1964-10/19/1965 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Tresidder/Bloch - Eurich/Bloch:, 2/8/1946-12/14/1948 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with University Administration:, 10/11/1945-8/31/1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - University Administration Matters:, 10/1945- ca. 5/1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Appointment Committee:, 11/18/1960-2/9/1961 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Appointment Committee:, 10/14/1961-1/9/1963 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Appointment Committee:, 1/11/1963-10/24/1963 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Appointment Committee:, 12/6/1963-4/29/1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Appointment Committee:, 5/31/1965-5/27/1966 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Appointment Committee:, 10/10/1966-4/24/1969 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Appointment Committee:, 4/11/1970-12/10/1971 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Radio Research Library Correspondence and Publications:, 11/19/1945-3/9/1946 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Research Corporation Correspondence:, 10/15/1945-7/16/1952 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Nuclear Physics Course for Engineers:, 7/11/1956-11/18/1956 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Legal Correspondence:, 7/23/1959-1/15/1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Legal Correspondence:, 1/18/1960-3/3/1960 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Legal Correspondence:, 3/4/1960-6/6/1960 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Legal Correspondence:, 6/6/1960-8/26/1960 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Legal Correspondence:, 8/26/1960-11/21/1960 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Legal Correspondence:, 12/13/1960-2/3/1961 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Legal Correspondence:, 3/8/1961-4/19/1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Legal Correspondence:, 5/1/1962-9/24/1962 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Varian Associates Consultancy Correspondence:, 6/8/1964-10/28/1968 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Elion v. Varian Associates:, 12/11/1961-12/12/1961 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Elion v. Bruker:, 12/16/1971-1/27/1972 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Bloch-Herzog Oil Detection:, 9/21/1962-10/15/1962 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Bloch-Varian License Agreements:, 3/17/1966-11/14/1968 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Bloch-Varian License Agreements:, 12/17/1968 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Bloch-Varian License Agreements Correspondence:, 4/9/1971-4/21/1971 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Patents:, 4/15/1955-1/22/1963 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Patent Applications: Bloch et al. (Patent Number 454,272) (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Faust-- Eine Historie (Strossbrigade des Institut teoretisk Fysik: Les Cent Contre Einstien:, 1932), 1931 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Bohr Commemoration Papers:, 7/8/1963-7/13/1963 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous and unknown (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Misc.):, 4/9/1980-2/8/1982 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Academic Freedom:, 11/1949-8/14/1952 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Letter to President Johnson on Biological/Chemical Warfare:, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Bloch-Cranston Correspondence, Notes:, 12/1973-12/10/1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Middle Eastern Affairs:, 11/21/1974-3/10/1979 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Dissertation: Paul Berdahl (Box 12, Folder nf)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit:, 9/2/1964-12/8/1964 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit:, 1/4/1965-5/11/1965 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit, Detailed Accounts:, 5/13/1965 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit:, 5/14/1965-8/2/1965 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit:, 8/3/1965-10/28/1965 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit, Review of the Bloch-Hansen Agreement:, 12/31/1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit:, 1/20/1966-4/27/1966 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit:, 5/3/1966-11/10/1966 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit:, 11/11/1966-9/7/1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit, Rubidium Magnetometer:, 11/15/1946-8/13/1951 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit, Rubidium Magnetometer:, 6/25/1952-5/26/1959 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit, Rubidium Magnetometer:, 2/1/1965-11/24/1965 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Varian-Bloch Audit, Rubidium Magnetometer: Varian Publications (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Patent application: G.B. 16233/55-U.S. 437,770 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Patent application: Swiss 20891-Fr. 693,996-U.S. 437,770 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Patent application: Swiss 5720/55-U.S. 437,770 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Patent application: Japan. 16446/55-U.S. 437,770 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Patent application: Can. 691,661-U.S. 454,272 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Patent application: Fr. 698474-U.S. 454,272 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Patent application: G.B. 24761/55-U.S. 454,272 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Patent application: Can. 686,196-U.S. 437,770 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Patent application: Japan. 24048/55-U.S. 454,272 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Patent application: Swiss 23789-U.S. 454,272 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Patent application: Swed. 7961/55-U.S. 454,272 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Patent application: W.Ger. B3709aIXb/42-U.S. 454,272 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Patent application: W.Ger. B36117IXb/42L-U.S. 437.770 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Gyromagnetic method and apparatus: patent application and correspondence (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Gyromagnetic method and apparatus: patent application (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Line narrowing gyromagnetic apparatus: patent application and correspondence, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Line narrowing gyromagnetic apparatus: patent records and correspondence, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Methods and means of chemical analysis: patent application and license (correspondence, agreements, notes) (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Nuclear induction: patent application and license (correspondence, agreements, notes) (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Nuclear resonance: copy of W. Hansen's notebook, (1945) (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Nuclear resonance: material for deposition, June 1959 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence regarding patent matters, 1950-1953 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding patent matters, 1951-1953 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Bloch and Hansen v. Perkin-Elmer: correspondence, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Bloch and Hansen v. Perkin-Elmer: correspondence, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Bloch and Hansen v. Perkin-Elmer: correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Bloch and Hansen v. Perkin-Elmer: correspondence, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Bloch and Hansen v. Perkin-Elmer: correspondence, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Varian Associates, agreement, January 1948 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Varian Associates, agreement, October 1953 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Bloch-Varian license agreement: report and correspondence, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Varian Associates, agreement, March 1954 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Varian Associates, agreement, May-June 1954 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Varian Associates, agreement, July 1954 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Varian Associates, agreement, August 1954 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence re: licence agreements, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Varian Associates, correspondence, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Varian Associates, correspondence, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Varian Associates, correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Varian Associates, correspondence, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Royalty statements and consultant fees, 1953-1958 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - U.S. National Commission for UNESCO, correspondence, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1960-1971 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1979-1983 and undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Some remarks about nuclear power, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Remarks at memorial for Daniel Mendelowitz, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Studies in CERN history, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Nuclear magnetic resonance, articles about (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Von Witzleben, H., Im Dienste Goethens..., 1977 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Von Witzleben, H., Damals in Weimar..., 1974 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Von Witzleben, H., Homoeopathie in der Zeit Goethes, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Jackson, J.D., The Nature of Intrinsic Magnetic Dipole Moments, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - SCIENCE AND TECHNION; a selection of major essays on science and society contributed to the TECHNION YEARBOOK; Ben Dibner, editor, 1959 (Box 17, Folder nf)